bozemandailychronicle.com 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy | Site | bozemandailychronicle.com

_Effective date May 22, 2018_

This Privacy Policy explains how your personally identifiable information is collected and used by the Bozeman Daily Chronicle, APG West, and affiliated websites, hereafter referred to as “Company”.

Our Company has a firm commitment to privacy. We take your privacy concerns seriously and want to make reasonable efforts to address them as we strive to offer our site visitors a high quality, interactive and personalized experience. This Privacy Policy explains our position on information gathering and how we intend to use and share any information we collect. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by our company through utilization of its various internet products.

 **You understand and agree that, by visiting this website and its affiliated sites, you are accepting, without modification, this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any portion of this Privacy Policy, then your only option is to not use our internet products.**

When you visit one of the Company’s websites, the Company collects and stores personally identifiable information such as your name, address, and e-mail address. The information that we collect and store about you depends on the page you visit and the services in which you elect to participate. We use this information to operate our services, improve the quality of our services, offer you opportunities we think will interest you, and better tailor the advertising you see from us to suit you. This information is not shared with anyone outside of our company and its affiliated companies except as provided for in this Privacy Policy or as explained at the time the information is collected. More specifics on the information we collect and how we use it are outlined within this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time by the Company and your continued use of the Company’s internet products means you agree to, without modification, the revisions. Should you object to any such modifications to this Privacy Policy or become dissatisfied with the Company’s internet products in any way, your only option is to immediately discontinue use of those products. Otherwise, continuing to use the service after the effective date means that you agree to be bound by the changes, without modification.

If you would like to discuss any concerns that you may have regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact ejohnston@apgwest.com.

## Information we collect

On occasion, you must provide some personally identifiable information in order to use some of our websites. Some examples are signing up for e-mail services, contest participation, online forums, placing an ad online or participating in online surveys, as well as other instances when you are required to submit personally identifiable information.

## Passive data collection and use

Like most websites, the Company also collects and logs information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to you, such as your IP address, the name and location of your ISP, the type and version of your browser, the length of time that you stay on our websites, search queries, and the average number of pages viewed. To better provide our services to you and to develop profiles that enable us to tailor services and its advertisements to your interests, we may correlate this information with other information about you, such as your registration information or newspaper subscription records. We may provide to third parties anonymous aggregated (non-personally identifiable) general information about our website and its users.

## Use of cookies

Most standard web browsers contain a feature called “cookies,” which allow a website to place information about a user’s visit to that website in a small data text file that is stored on the user’s computer. Our use of cookie technology will likely be transparent to you and is used to recognize you and hold information from one visit to the next in an effort to increase your ease of use and to allow us to better understand how people use our products. You can turn the cookies feature off by using your browser preference options.

Some of our third-party content providers also may place a cookie on your computer. Those cookies are controlled by the content provider, and you should refer to that provider’s privacy policy for further information regarding its use of cookies and about your options not to accept them.

In addition, advertisers may elect to use other advertising companies to serve their ads on our websites, and advertisers themselves may also place a cookie on a user’s computer. We do not have access to the cookies or their contents that are placed by advertisers or by third-party advertising companies. We, therefore, recommend that you read the privacy policy of each and every website you visit or with which you interact.

## Behavioral Targeting

From time to time, the Company or its business partners may use collected data to optimize our offers of products and services to you. If you desire not to participate in this effort, please contact ejohnston@apgwest.com with your request to opt out.

## Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements

Our Company expects its partners, providers of content and services and advertisers to respect the privacy of its users. Be aware, however, that third parties, including our partners, providers of content and services, advertisers and others accessible through our site may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. You should use common sense when you navigate the web and be aware of when you travel outside of our website. In addition, you should carefully review the applicable privacy policies of each website you visit and each web service you use.

## Electronic commerce

For certain electronic commerce services on our websites, such as placing classified ads electronically or subscribing to the print or electronic version of the newspaper, we require additional information. To complete these transactions, we may collect information from you such as your name, credit card number and other financial information. We endeavor to protect the security of your payment information during transmission by using technology, which protects information you submit. Our Company will use the credit card and shipping information for the purpose of completing the transaction and does not provide this information to third parties except for the providers of the transaction processing and the issuers of credit cards in order to process the transaction, or as otherwise set forth in this policy.

## State and Federal Privacy Rights

In certain jurisdictions, you may have the right to receive: a) information identifying any third-party company(ies) to whom our Company may have disclosed personal information pertaining to you and your family for that company’s direct marketing purposes; b) a description of the categories of personal information disclosed; and c) other enumerated information. To obtain such information, please e-mail your request to ejohnston@apgwest.com.

## Revisions

From time to time, and without notice, the Company may revise the policies set out herein. The effective date of the current policy is set out below the title and all users our the Company’s websites are bound to the terms and conditions in effect as of the date of use.

If you have any questions or comments about our policies, we may be reached c/o Eric Johnston, APG West, 1215 Anderson Rd,Mt Vernon, WA 98274; tel. 206-284-4424.

## Prohibited Uses

This Site is not intended for use by persons located within the European Economic Area (EEA). We do not request or accept personal information concerning or supplied by persons who are located within the EEA at the time they access this Site. If you have accessed this Site from within the EEA, you should immediately discontinue your use. If you have supplied personal information to us in violation of this provision, whether through the registration of new user accounts or otherwise, please contact us at gdpr@apwest.com.

####  [](https://www.bozemandailychronicle.com/calendar/)
